welcome to another installment of the
right chest and redux video series if
you haven't been following along it will
probably be much easier to start at the
beginning since each video deals on
where the previous video by staff and
remember to get up to speed on Redux
itself you really can't beat ya diode
videos
paradoxes creator Dan aber muss
when we left off last time we had
created a redox or created as super
basic producer and has our story into a
tag so that we can get the state and
grab properties off of that state object
this time we're going to build on that
example we're going to introduce some
actions so the first thing I want to do
is with this sample output tag on it
clean it up and get rid of that excess
paragraph really need that I know what
I'm going to do isn't gonna add a forum
is going to add some interactivity I'm
gonna do that and redux
by dispatching actions so create a forum
for that forms on Submit you want to add
a change title method and we'll have
that sort a just a moment and my form
also needs an input will take peace
attacks were gonna call that new title
and we're gonna give our former button
so that we can submit that new title
down at the bottom of my tag gonna have
my script tags and I wanna call change
title and for now just so we can make
sure that everything is wired up and
everything's been tied to properly
monitor console inside of change title
and I'm gonna go over my browser and
refresh your notice that I have my
default title and my new form of tools
escaped a new value into my forum and i
got a click Change title I should see
the new value logged onto the console so
now that I know my form is properly
wired up I'm gonna go back into my
sample output tank to remove that
console log and what I want to do is I
wanna get access to my store so called
that through this upstart store and I
want to use the stores dispatch method
to send in and then out to the reducer
or more appropriately send them action
to the reducer so dispatches gonna send
an action object
that object is gonna have a tight
property but I properly as hell we're
gonna decide what to do with this
particular action and because I'm trying
to change the title and I have a foreign
value has gone to pass and data along
with the object so aside from the type
I'm also gonna give it a property and
can assign the value of new title that
value to the data property now that I
have that wired up they can go back to
index that Jas and mi reducer I'm gonna
have to consult with action so we can
see what's happening so got back to my
browser refresh open up the console
again
it's a value this is a test into my
title going to submit the form and we'll
see that we get an object logged out so
the console with the title you have
changed title signed it in the object we
pass to dispatch and we had a property
where the value that we tighten to our
employees so we know that our action is
making it to the reducer for now let's
do something with it so in my producer
at a switch because 320 handle multiple
actions we want to change our behavior
based on the types passed in and I want
to add a case may switch for change
title and because where it is or has to
return to state no matter what must have
been added to folk case then take my
return state that I had as the only
functionality in the reducer method and
I'm gonna move that at 200 to fall so
that if we get an action and we don't
match on the tape will return this state
as it is and everything will continue to
function so in the change title case I
want to create a new state and I'm going
to give it a title properly assign
action that data has the value that
title on our return new state and with
that in place to go to the browser
refresh
a forum with my new title I submit the
form it should update the title of my
tach so just to recap submitting the
form and sample output cause change
title which uses the Redux stories
dispatch method as long in action object
their action object has a type and a
piece of data which represents the new
title
producer I switch on that action type
when I hit the change table case I
create a new state sign the title
property of that action that data
returned that new state and my sample
output eg when it's updated
called get state again and receive the
new value of title so the problem with
this new state set up is that this is
gonna raise her in an object that only
has a title property in a more complex
application for state will contain other
values that are being used in other
parts of the state tree so you want to
make sure that we only change the value
were concerned with and still return a
full version of the state only are
changes reflected so we want to do some
refactoring
and I want to use object at a sign and I
want to take the state and an object
with my new title and won a combined
them into a new object that gets
returned to represent the new state and
if we go over to the browser we can
refresh again and get our default title
that we start with value and everything
I'll continue to wear and that we
verified that we didn't break anything
or exaggerating we can go back and read
code and remove this console dialogue
thank you for watching hope you found
this video helpful and be sure to keep
an eye out for the next video in the
series